The next section is about graph algorithms.
I'm sure you've all seen the basic graph algorithms before;
DFS for depth-first search,
BFS for breadth-first search and Dijkstra's single source shortest path algorithm.
We'll do a quick review of how DFS is used to
find the connected components of an undirected graph,
and then we'll build on that to look at connectivity in directed graphs.
We'll use DFS to find the strongly connected components of directed graphs.
These are the analog of connected components in directed graphs.
And then we'll see an application of
our strongly connected component algorithm to solve the two set problem.
Next, we'll look at the minimum spanning tree problem, MSTs.
You've likely seen that Kruskal's and Prim's algorithm before for finding an MST.
We'll look at the correctness behind these algorithms.
Finally, we'll look at the PageRank algorithm.
This is the algorithm that looks at the Web graph and assigns
weights to vertices or webpages.
It's a measure of their importance.
This algorithm was devised by Brin and Page,
and it's at the heart of Google's search engine.
To understand the PageRank algorithm,
I'll first give you a quick primer on Markov chains,
and then you'll see how it relates to strongly connected components.